Namaskar.
大家好。
I'm a movie star, I'm 51 years of age,
我是一位电影明星， 今年51岁了。
and I don't use Botox as yet.
但我还不到要打肉毒杆菌的地步。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
So I'm clean, but I do behave like you saw like a 21-year-old in my movies.
尽管如此， 我戏里戏外都当自己21岁，
Yeah, I do that.
对，没错
I sell dreams, and I peddle love to millions of people back home in India
我贩卖梦想， 也向数百万的印度人传递着爱
who assume that I'm the best lover in the world.
他们都相信我是 这个世界上最棒的梦中情人。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
If you don't tell anyone, I'm going to tell you I'm not,
偷偷告诉你，其实我不是
but I never let that assumption go away.
但是我宁可大家 一直相信这个误会
(Laughter)
（笑声）
I've also been made to understand
我也听说，
there are lots of you here who haven't seen my work,
今天在座的很多人， 从来没看过我的电影，
and I feel really sad for you.
我真为你们感到遗憾。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
(Applause)
（掌声）
That doesn't take away from the fact that I'm completely self-obsessed,
好吧 我承认我是有些自恋，
as a movie star should be.
搞得好像电影明星 本来都这么自以为是似的。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
That's when my friends, Chris and Juliet called me here
这就是为什么我的朋友 克里斯和朱莉叶找我来这里
to speak about the future "you."
来聊聊未来的“你们"
Naturally, it follows I'm going to speak about the present me.
自然而然地， 我就要先聊聊现在的“我"
(Laughter)
(笑声）
Because I truly believe that humanity is a lot like me.
因为我真的相信， 人性和我很像。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
It is. It is.
它就是，就像是，
It's an aging movie star,
一个正在老去的电影明星，
grappling with all the newness around itself,
一边要想着与周围的新生事物抗争，
wondering whether it got it right in the first place,
一边又要考虑自己 从一开始到底学得对不对，
and still trying to find a way
还要想办法，
to keep on shining regardless.
保持我表面的光鲜亮丽。
I was born in a refugee colony in the capital city of India, New Delhi.
我出生在印度首都 新德里的一个难民营里，
And my father was a freedom fighter.
而我的父亲是一位自由战士，
My mother was, well, just a fighter like mothers are.
我的母亲呢，就像所有的母亲一样 也活得像个战士
And much like the original homo sapiens,
听起来有点像是原始人，
we struggled to survive.
我们为了生存而苦苦挣扎。
When I was in my early 20s,
在我20岁出头的时候，
I lost both my parents,
我爸妈就过世了，
which I must admit seems a bit careless of me now,
对于现在的我来说， 不得不承认我有点忘了。
but --
但是 -
(Laughter)
（笑声）
I do remember the night my father died,
我依稀记得的是我爸过世那晚，
and I remember the driver of a neighbor who was driving us to the hospital.
我记得是一位邻居载我们到医院的。
He mumbled something about "dead people don't tip so well"
他一个人喃喃着， “人死了就收不到小费了。”
and walked away into the dark.
然后一个人消失在了黑夜中
And I was only 14 then,
那时我才14岁，
and I put my father's dead body in the back seat of the car,
我把我爸的尸体放在后座，
and my mother besides me,
我的妈妈坐在副驾驶上，
I started driving back from the hospital to the house.
我就准备开车要从医院回家，
And in the middle of her quiet crying, my mother looked at me and she said,
我妈哭到一半， 忽然转头问我，
"Son, when did you learn to drive?"
“儿子，你怎么会开车的?”
And I thought about it and realized, and I said to my mom,
然后我想了一下， 告诉我妈妈说，
"Just now, Mom."
“刚刚学会的，妈妈。”
(Laughter)
（笑声）
So from that night onwards,
自从那天晚上之后，
much akin to humanity in its adolescence,
就好像是人性 步入了青春期一样，
I learned the crude tools of survival.
我学会了最基本的生存方式，
And the framework of life was very, very simple then, to be honest.
老实说，其实这些 生活的条条框框不难学。
You know, you just ate what you got
反正你有什么吃什么，
and did whatever you were told to do.
人家叫你做什么就做什么。
I thought celiac was a vegetable,
我曾以为 ”腹腔 (Celiac)“ 是一种蔬菜，
and vegan, of course, was Mr. Spock's lost comrade in "Star Trek."
“素食主义者(Vegan)" 是电影 星际迷航里的“瓦肯族 (Vulcan)”。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
You married the first girl that you dated,
我还相信你们都会和 自己第一个约会的女孩结婚；
and you were a techie if you could fix the carburetor in your car.
相信会修汽车化油器， 就算是个汽车专家了；
I really thought that gay was a sophisticated English word for happy.
天真地以为英文单词 "gay"  （同性恋）就只是开心的意思；
And Lesbian, of course, was the capital of Portugal, as you all know.
理所当然地以为"Lesbian"  （女同性恋）就是葡萄牙首都里斯本（Lisbon）。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
Where was I?
好吧，我扯远了。
We relied on systems
我们依赖着的体制生活，
created through the toil and sacrifice of generations before
是祖祖辈辈们 用血汗创造出来的成果，
to protect us,
为了来庇护我们的；
and we felt that governments actually worked for our betterment.
我们相信政府一定在 为人民的美好未来而努力；
Science was simple and logical,
科学是简单而富有逻辑，
Apple was still then just a fruit
苹果也还只是一种水果，
owned by Eve first and then Newton,
先被夏娃咬了一口， 之后又砸到了牛顿，
not by Steve Jobs, until then.
还不是现在斯蒂芬乔布斯的品牌。
And "Eureka!" was what you screamed
而阿基米德大喊着：“我知道了！”，
when you wanted to run naked on the streets.
其实只是想在街上裸奔的借口。
You went wherever life took you for work,
你为了工作随遇而安，
and people were mostly welcoming of you.
大家大多都对你很友善。
Migration was a term then
迁徙也只是一个词语
still reserved for Siberian cranes, not human beings.
用来形容西伯利亚 白鹤飞越国界，而非难民。
Most importantly, you were who you were
更重要的是， 你可以做你自己，
and you said what you thought.
你可以说你想要说的。
Then in my late 20s,
然后在我将近30岁时，
I shifted to the sprawling metropolis of Mumbai,
我搬到了热闹而繁华的孟买都市区，
and my framework,
我的人生，
like the newly industrialized aspirational humanity,
就像人性进入了工业革命，
began to alter.
发生了翻天覆地的变化，
In the urban rush for a new, more embellished survival,
要在千变万化的城市中寻求生存，
things started to look a little different.
一切都变得不一样了。
I met people who had descended from all over the world,
我遇见了来自世界各地的人，
faces, races, genders, money-lenders.
来自不同的种族， 拥有不同的面孔，性别，财富
Definitions became more and more fluid.
我的价值观开始改变，
Work began to define you at that time
你的职业成了定义你的标准，
in an overwhelmingly equalizing manner,
这一切变得无比客观，
and all the systems started to feel less reliable to me,
所有的体制对于 我来说都变得不再可靠，
almost too thick to hold on
变得很难去
to the diversity of mankind
去解释人的多样性，
and the human need to progress and grow.
而且人类也是需要 不断进步、成长的。
Ideas were flowing with more freedom and speed.
许多想法变得更加自由， 传播速度也越来越快。
And I experienced the miracle of human innovation and cooperation,
我经历了人类创新与合作的奇迹，
and my own creativity,
还有我自己创造的奇迹，
when supported by the resourcefulness of this collective endeavor,
当我得到所有的支持和资源，
catapulted me into superstardom.
是它们把我推上了巨星的位置。
I started to feel that I had arrived,
我开始意识到我成功了，
and generally, by the time I was 40, I was really, really flying.
在我40岁左右， 我感觉自己真的就像是身处云端
I was all over the place.
我变得无所不在， 无所不能。
You know? I'd done 50 films by then
你知道，到目前为止 我拍了50部电影，
and 200 songs,
和超过200首歌舞插曲。
and I'd been knighted by the Malaysians.
马来西亚授予我勋爵，
I had been given the highest civil honor by the French government,
法国政府给我颁发 最高的平民荣誉，
the title of which for the life of me I can't pronounce even until now.
虽然我至今还念不出 那个头衔的名字。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
I'm sorry, France, and thank you, France, for doing that.
抱歉，法国，还是非常 感激你们颁奖给我。
But much bigger than that, I got to meet Angelina Jolie --
但是比那个更大的荣幸是 我见到了安吉丽娜朱莉(Angelina Jolie) -
(Laughter)
（笑声）
for two and a half seconds.
虽然就只有两秒半
(Laughter)
（笑声）
And I'm sure she also remembers that encounter somewhere.
但是我觉得她一定 记得我们在哪里见过，
OK, maybe not.
好吧 也许没有，
And I sat next to Hannah Montana on a round dinner table
我也曾和孟汉娜 (Hannah Montana) 同桌共进晚餐，
with her back towards me most of the time.
虽然她几乎都是背对着我的。
Like I said, I was flying, from Miley to Jolie,
就像我说的，我身处云端， 从麦莉到朱莉，我的事业到达了巅峰，
and humanity was soaring with me.
人性也随之驰骋 在这黄金的岁月里，
We were both pretty much flying off the handle, actually.
可以说我和人性的发展 几乎是都到达了巅峰，
And then you all know what happened.
之后发生的变化各位都知道，
The internet happened.
网络出现了。
I was in my late 40s,
在我快要50岁的时候，
and I started tweeting like a canary in a birdcage
我默默地玩起了推特，
and assuming that, you know, people who peered into my world
然后期待圈外人也能 有兴趣窥探我的内在世界，
would admire it
或者欣赏
for the miracle I believed it to be.
我所相信的那些奇迹。
But something else awaited me and humanity.
但是事情并没有 如我和人们所预料的，
You know, we had expected an expansion of ideas and dreams
我们以为想法和梦想
with the enhanced connectivity of the world.
会随着网络扩散出去。
We had not bargained for the village-like enclosure of thought,
没想到的是，
of judgment, of definition
那些故步自封的成见、断论和解读，
that flowed from the same place
也随着自由与思想的革命，
that freedom and revolution was taking place in.
一同产生。
Everything I said took a new meaning.
我说的每一句话都会 以不同的方式被解读，
Everything I did -- good, bad, ugly --
我做的每一件事 -  不论好坏还是美丑 -
was there for the world to comment upon and judge.
就在那里让全世界去评论和判断。
As a matter of fact, everything I didn't say or do also
事实上我没做过的事或说过的话，
met with the same fate.
也要面临着同样的命运。
Four years ago,
四年前，
my lovely wife Gauri and me decided to have a third child.
我和我太太高丽决定要第三个孩子。
It was claimed on the net
结果网上居然说，
that he was the love child
那是我的大儿子(Aryan Khan)的小孩，
of our first child
我的大儿子，
who was 15 years old.
他四年前只有15岁，
Apparently, he had sown his wild oats with a girl
网上居然说， 是他在罗马尼亚
while driving her car in Romania.
和他的女友搞车震， 播下的野种。
And yeah, there was a fake video to go with it.
而且啊 还流出一段假视频，
And we were so disturbed as a family.
我们全家都不堪其扰，
My son, who is 19 now,
我的儿子，现在19岁了，
even now when you say "hello" to him,
现在就算你只是 跟他打个招呼说“你好",
he just turns around and says,
他都会马上说，
"But bro, I didn't even have a European driving license."
“嘿伙计，我根本没有欧洲驾照。”
(Laughter)
（笑声）
Yeah.
是啊
In this new world,
在这个崭新的世界里，
slowly, reality became virtual and virtual became real,
慢慢地真假变得难以区分。
and I started to feel
我开始觉得，
that I could not be who I wanted to be or say what I actually thought,
我不能做我自己， 我不能随便发表我的想法，
and humanity at this time
而此时的人性
completely identified with me.
就跟我一模一样。
I think both of us were going through our midlife crisis,
和我一起步入了中年危机，
and humanity, like me, was becoming an overexposed prima donna.
人性就像我，变成了一个 整天被狗仔队追赶的主角
I started to sell everything,
我开始贩卖一切，
from hair oil to diesel generators.
从发油到柴油发电机。
Humanity was buying everything
而人性开始收买一切，
from crude oil to nuclear reactors.
从原油到核反应堆。
You know, I even tried to get into a skintight superhero suit
你知道 我甚至 还想过穿超人紧身衣
to reinvent myself.
为了重新塑身。
I must admit I failed miserably.
我必须承认我彻底失败了，
And just an aside I want to say on behalf of all the Batmen, Spider-Men
在此打个岔， 代表蝙蝠侠，蜘蛛人，
and Supermen of the world,
还有这个世界的超人们，
you have to commend them,
请各位把掌声送给他们，
because it really hurts in the crotch, that superhero suit.
因为穿超人装，胯下超疼。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
Yeah, I'm being honest. I need to tell you this here.
我忍不住要提一下，
Really.
真的很痛。
And accidentally, I happened to even invent a new dance form
于是一不小心， 我就发明了我的新舞步，
which I didn't realize, and it became a rage.
无意间成了一股新的潮流。
So if it's all right,
不介意的话，
and you've seen a bit of me, so I'm quite shameless, I'll show you.
反正你们也知道我脸皮比较厚， 我要跳一下。
It was called the Lungi dance.
这叫做腰布舞 (Lungi dance《钦奈快车》歌舞）
So if it's all right, I'll just show you. I'm talented otherwise.
不介意的话，我在这里 给你们秀两招，虽然没有很厉害。
(Cheers)
（欢呼）
So it went something like this.
所以跳起来就是这样子的。
Lungi dance. Lungi dance. Lungi dance. Lungi dance.
（腰布舞）隆基丹斯 隆基丹斯 ...
隆基丹斯 隆基丹斯 ...
Lungi dance. Lungi dance. Lungi dance. Lungi.
... 隆基丹斯 隆基丹斯 隆基。
That's it. It became a rage.
就是这舞步，风靡一时。
(Cheers)
（欢呼）
It really did.
真的很火。
Like you notice, nobody could make any sense of what was happening except me,
除了我之外， 真的没人知道为什么会这样，
and I didn't give a damn, really,
不过我也不在乎，真的。
because the whole world, and whole humanity,
因为整个世界，所有的人
seemed as confused and lost as I was.
其实都和我一样茫然失措。
I didn't give up then.
但我没有放弃，
I even tried to reconstruct my identity on the social media
我试图在社交媒体上 重新塑造自己的形象，
like everyone else does.
就像其他人一样。
I thought if I put on philosophical tweets out there
我认为如果我常发 一些有哲理的推文，
people will think I'm with it,
人们也许会觉得我很有内涵，
but some of the responses I got from those tweets
但我也收到一些回复，
were extremely confusing acronyms which I didn't understand. You know?
我真的完全看不懂，你知道吗?
ROFL, LOL.
像那类缩写或网络新词  ROFL（笑死我了）, LOL（笑出声）等
"Adidas," somebody wrote back to one of my more thought-provoking tweets
还有“Adidas”，有人在我 非常有哲理的推文下回复这
and I was wondering why would you name a sneaker,
我还想我发的和运动品牌 阿迪达斯有什么关系？
I mean, why would you write back the name of a sneaker to me?
我的意思是为什么你要 给我留言阿迪达斯？
And I asked my 16-year-old daughter, and she enlightened me.
然后我去问我16岁的女儿， 她一下子点拨了我。
"Adidas" now means "All day I dream about sex."
“Adidas”的意思是 "我整天想着做爱"的英文缩写
(Laughter)
（笑声）
Really.
真的。
I didn't know if you know that.
你们知道这个吗。
So I wrote back, "WTF" in bold to Mr. Adidas,
所以我就回复阿迪达斯先生， “WTF”（搞什么鬼啊）的缩写
thanking secretly that some acronyms and things won't change at all.
好险我居然还是知道一些缩写的。
WTF.
WTF (What The F*)  搞什么鬼啊
But here we are.
然后来到了现在，
I am 51 years old, like I told you,
我之前告诉你， 我今年51岁，
and mind-numbing acronyms notwithstanding,
而我却还在研究 那些荒谬的缩写含义，
I just want to tell you
我只是想告诉你，
if there has been a momentous time for humanity to exist,
如果人性真的有 那么一刻是存在的，
it is now,
那么就是现在，
because the present you is brave.
因为现在的你是勇敢的，
The present you is hopeful.
现在的你是充满希望的，
The present you is innovative and resourceful,
现在的你是拥有着创意和智慧的，
and of course, the present you is annoyingly indefinable.
当然现在的你也充满着无限的可能。
And in this spell-binding,
此刻在这个迷幻
imperfect moment of existence,
却又不完美的存在，
feeling a little brave just before I came here,
让我在上台前更有勇气，
I decided to take a good, hard look at my face.
我决定好好凝视着我的面容，
And I realized that I'm beginning to look more and more
然后我越看越仔细，
like the wax statue of me at Madame Tussaud's.
就像在看我自己在 杜莎夫人蜡像馆的蜡像一样。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
Yeah, and in that moment of realization,
是的，就在那一刻 我灵光一闪，
I asked the most central and pertinent question to humanity and me:
我问了人性和我自己 最关键的问题：
Do I need to fix my face?
我需要整容吗？
Really. I'm an actor, like I told you,
真的，就像我所告诉你的， 作为一个演员，
a modern expression of human creativity.
是人类创意现代化的展示。
The land I come from
我的家乡，
is the source of inexplicable but very simple spirituality.
印度是一个神秘又单纯的灵性之地。
In its immense generosity,
因为它的慷慨和包容，
India decided somehow
印度不知怎么地，
that I, the Muslim son of a broke freedom fighter
让一个穷困潦倒的、穆斯林的儿子
who accidentally ventured into the business of selling dreams,
意外地做起了贩卖梦想的生意，
should become its king of romance,
成了浪漫之王的代名词，
the "Badhshah of Bollywood,"
成了宝莱坞之王，
the greatest lover the country has ever seen ...
成了这国家前所未有的梦中情人...
with this face.
用这样一张脸。
Yeah.
是的 就是这样
(Laughter)
（笑声）
Which has alternately been described as ugly, unconventional,
甚至可以被描述为有点丑的， 有点标新立异的，
and strangely, not chocolatey enough.
有点奇怪的脸， 但还好不算太黑。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
The people of this ancient land
来自这片古老土地的人们，
embraced me in their limitless love,
用他们无尽的爱拥抱着我，
and I've learned from these people
我从他们身上学到了，
that neither power nor poverty
有权有势也好，落魄潦倒也好，
can make your life more magical
都不能使你的生活变得更加精彩
or less tortuous.
或是少些波折。
I've learned from the people of my country
我从我的同胞们那里学到了，
that the dignity of a life,
作为一个生命，
a human being, a culture, a religion, a country
一个人，一种文化， 一种宗教，一个国家的自豪
actually resides in its ability
其实真真切切地渗透在
for grace and compassion.
人们对包容之心与怜悯之情的追求。
I've learned that whatever moves you,
我学到了无论是什么感动了你，
whatever urges you to create, to build,
无论是什么激励着你， 驱使着你去创造，去塑造，
whatever keeps you from failing,
是什么让你从跌倒中爬起，
whatever helps you survive,
是什么让你从绝境中重生，
is perhaps the oldest and the simplest emotion known to mankind,
都可能是我们所人类知晓的 最简单的、最古老的感情，
and that is love.
那就是爱。
A mystic poet from my land famously wrote,
一位来自我故乡的 神秘主义诗人曾写道，
(Recites poem in Hindi)
（朗诵印地语诗句...）
(Poem ends)
（...诗结束）
Which loosely translates into that whatever --
大致翻译一下的意思是 -
yeah, if you know Hindi, please clap, yeah.
对啊，如果你听得懂印地语， 可以先鼓掌。
(Applause)
（掌声）
It's very difficult to remember.
有点难记得，
Which loosely translates into actually saying
大致翻译一下，意思是说
that all the books of knowledge that you might read
你从书里汲取知识之精华，
and then go ahead and impart your knowledge
然后把知识传递下去，
through innovation, through creativity, through technology,
用在发明，创造，还有科技，
but mankind will never be the wiser about its future
但这样依旧无法使人类的 未来走向更深切的智慧，
unless it is coupled with a sense of love and compassion for their fellow beings.
除非他们能对同胞们 怀揣着爱与关怀之心，
The two and a half alphabets which form the word "प्रेम,"
这两个半的字母 构成了印地语里的“प्रेम”，
which means "love,"
那意味着“爱”。
if you are able to understand that
如果你能真正理解它，
and practice it,
并把它记在心中，
that itself is enough to enlighten mankind.
并身体力行。
So I truly believe the future "you"
所以我真的相信未来的“你们",
has to be a you that loves.
必须是一个愿意 “去爱”和“接受爱”的你
Otherwise it will cease to flourish.
否则这个世界的未来将黯淡失色，
It will perish in its own self-absorption.
一切都会在自我的沉醉中消失殆尽。
So you may use your power
所以你可以用你的力量
to build walls
去筑起心中高高的围墙，
and keep people outside,
把他人都拒之门外，
or you may use it to break barriers and welcome them in.
或者你可以用它 来打破壁垒，欢迎他们；
You may use your faith
你可以用你的信念，
to make people afraid
让人心生畏惧，
and terrify them into submission,
把他们吓到无奈地屈从于你，
or you can use it to give courage to people
或者你可以用信念去鼓舞他人，
so they rise to the greatest heights of enlightenment.
让他们也能获得深刻的启迪；
You can use your energy
你可以用你的能源，
to build nuclear bombs and spread the darkness of destruction,
去制造核导弹， 散播毁灭性的黑暗，
or you can use it to spread the joy of light to millions.
或者你可以把喜悦之光 传递给成千上万的人们；
You may filthy up the oceans callously and cut down all the forests.
你可以去污染海洋， 无情地砍下所有的森林，
You can destroy the ecology,
你可以破坏生态的平衡，
or turn to them with love
或者用爱去浇灌这一切
and regenerate life from the waters and trees.
让所有的树木和水源获得新生；
You may land on Mars
你可以登陆火星
and build armed citadels,
去建立军事的堡垒，
or you may look for life-forms and species to learn from and respect.
或是怀着求知和尊敬 去寻找新生命和物种；
And you can use all the moneys we all have earned
你还可以用赚来的所有钱
to wage futile wars
去发动百害而无一利的战争
and give guns in the hands of little children
把枪支交在年幼的孩童手中
to kill each other with,
教他们互相残杀，
or you can use it
或者你可以用那些钱
to make more food
去提供更多的食物，
to fill their stomachs with.
去帮助饥肠辘辘的人们。
My country has taught me
我的国家教给我，
the capacity for a human being to love is akin to godliness.
一个人拥有爱的能力， 就像是对神灵万物的敬畏，
It shines forth in a world
爱的荣光足以普照大地，
which civilization, I think, already has tampered too much with.
照亮这个已经没有文明可言的世界。
In the last few days, the talks here, the wonderful people
在过去的几天里， 无数才华横溢的演讲者在这里
coming and showing their talent,
带来了他们各种精彩的分享。
talking about individual achievements, the innovation, the technology,
有他们的个人成就、创新、技术、
the sciences, the knowledge we are gaining by being here
科学和知识。 光是坐在台下就收获无数，
in the presence of TED Talks and all of you
这归功于TED Talk平台 还有所有的你们。
are reasons enough for us to celebrate the future "us."
这让我们都有足够的理由 去庆祝未来的“你我”。
But within that celebration
但是在欢庆的同时，
the quest to cultivate our capacity for love and compassion
不要忘了去培养爱和怜悯的能力，
has to assert itself, has to assert itself,
这是我们需要珍惜的能力， 让它们得以展现，
just as equally.
缺一不可。
So I believe the future "you"
所以我相信未来的“你们”，
is an infinite you.
是一个充满着无限可能的“你”。
It's called a chakra in India, like a circle.
在印度我把称之为 “心之轮回”(Chakra)，就像是圆，
It ends where it begins from to complete itself.
周而复始，生生不息，
A you that perceives time and space differently
一个用全新的角度 去感受时空奥妙的“你"，
understands both
同时明白，
your unimaginable
你也拥有无法想象的潜能，
and fantastic importance
和无与伦比的重要性，
and your complete unimportance in the larger context of the universe.
但在整个浩瀚的宇宙中， 又显得那么的微不足道。
A you that returns back
我还相信那是一个能回首的“你”
to the original innocence of humanity,
去寻回人性本身的天真无邪，
which loves from the purity of heart,
用孩童般的初心去热爱世界，
which sees from the eyes of truth,
用新生般的眼睛去看透真相，
which dreams from the clarity of an untampered mind.
用最澄澈的心灵去追寻梦想，
The future "you" has to be
我相信未来的“你们"一定会
like an aging movie star
像是我这个正在老去的电影明星，
who has been made to believe that there is a possibility
他相信这个世界拥有的可能，
of a world which is completely,
拥有的机会， 它能让全世界毫无保留地、
wholly, self-obsessively
完完全全地、痴迷般地
in love with itself.
去热爱自己。
A world -- really, it has to be a you
这个世界 - 真的， 必须是一个由你
to create a world
去创造的世界，
which is its own best lover.
而唯有你才是它最好的爱人。
That I believe, ladies and gentlemen,
所以我相信， 女士们先生们，
should be the future "you."
这才是大家未来的目标。
Thank you very much.
谢谢大家。
Shukriya.
谢谢。
(Applause)
（掌声）
Thank you.
谢谢。
(Applause)
（掌声）
Thank you.
谢谢。
(Applause)
（掌声）